when I bought my first digital camera
当我买了第一台数码相机的时候
the first thing I did was Google the
我做的第一件事是用谷歌搜索
most optimal settings for it many of the
最适合它的设置许多
good looking people on YouTube
YouTube上的帅哥们
recommended very specific settings such
推荐非常具体的设置 如
as changing the color space or reducing
如改变色彩空间或缩小
contrast and sharpness but no
对比度和清晰度 但没有
explanations to why those settings
对为什么这些设置的解释
needed to be said
需要说的是
I think understanding the why will clear
我认为理解其中的原因将会很清楚
up some of the misconceptions about
纠正一些关于
camera native files also known as raw
相机原生文件 也称为RAW
files just a side note I'll have to keep
文件只是一个附注 我将不得不保留
saying raw but remember that I mean
说得生硬 但请记住我的意思是
camera native files after all each
摄像机原生文件之后
camera model produces a different file
相机型号会生成不同的文件
and it's not some Global open
这不是什么全球公开赛
interchangeable format I think raw is
可互换的格式我认为RAW是
misleading and confusing
误导和混淆
but hey if that helps to get the point
但是 嘿 如果这有助于抓住重点的话
across I'll continue saying roll
在另一边 我会继续说翻滚
button tree aside I can pretty much sum
撇开纽扣树不谈 我几乎可以算出
up the entirety of this video in one
将此视频的全部内容合而为一
sentence color space setting sharpness
句子色彩空间设置清晰度
contrast saturation settings and the
对比饱和度设置和
white balance setting has no effect on
白平衡设置不会影响
the data that is captured by the sensor
传感器捕获的数据
while capturing raw files
在捕获原始文件时
now if you don't believe me and I hope
现在如果你不相信我 我希望
you don't stick around for a few minutes
你不会逗留几分钟
while I climb down the ladder of image
当我沿着形象的阶梯往下爬时
making I have already dissected the
使我已经解剖了
camera native raw file in another video
另一个视频中的摄像机原生RAW文件
where I talked about the cause of ping
在那里我谈到了ping的原因
highlights the first part might be
第一部分的亮点可能是
beneficial to watch as well but a lot of
看起来也很有用 但也有很多
it will be repeated here and there
它将在这里和那里重复
repetition is the illusion of knowledge
重复是知识的幻觉
after all let's start from the beginning
毕竟 让我们从头开始吧
the camera
摄像机
when you turn on the raw mode in your
当您在中打开原始模式时
camera you usually have a choice raw
相机你通常有一个原始的选择
only raw plus jpeg or jpeg only this is
仅RAW加jpeg或jpeg仅此为
the important bit
重要的一点是
even though we select raw only the
即使我们只选择RAW
camera will embed a JPEG preview image
摄像头将嵌入JPEG预览图像
into the file so you can well preview it
到文件中 这样您就可以很好地预览它
otherwise as raw data file is data you
否则 因为原始数据文件就是您的数据
could not preview it in good phase so
无法以良好的状态预览它 因此
the camera takes the settings that it
摄像机采用它所设置的
would apply to a JPEG and applies those
将应用于JPEG 并应用那些
settings to the raw preview image that
设置为原始预览图像
preview is a formed image but a raw data
预览是形成的图像 而不是原始数据
file is just captured data it is very
文件是刚刚捕获的数据 它非常
important to disconnect these two things
重要的是要把这两件事分开
as it is where most of the confusion
因为它是最令人困惑的地方
stems from
源于
so the settings namely white balance
所以设置即白平衡
color profile picture settings will be
颜色配置文件图片设置将为
applied to the preview of the raw file
应用于原始文件的预览
but not its data some of the settings
但不是它的数据的一些设置
you set in camera will be written as a
您在摄像机中设置的内容将被写入为
note for the photo editing software but
照片编辑软件注意事项 但
in no way will it affect the actual
它不会以任何方式影响实际
captured data
捕获的数据
okay let's put that to the test
好的 让我们来测试一下
first let's take a baseline shot of this
首先 让我们来做一次基线拍摄
Polaroid I have set the iso to 6500k
宝丽来我已将iso设置为6500k
color space to srgb
颜色空间到sRGB
and creative style to standard with the
和创造性的风格 与
default settings
默认设置
now let's randomize these settings
现在让我们随机化这些设置
I'll completely break the white balance
我会完全打破白平衡
setting by going it's custom and doing
通过去设置它是定制的和做的
whatever it takes to make it look as
不惜一切代价让它看起来
weird as possible
尽可能地怪异
same with the creative style let's
创意风格也一样 让我们
increase the contrast increase the
增加对比度增加
saturation and increase the sharpness
饱和度和提高清晰度
lastly let's swap to Adobe RGB
最后 让我们切换到Adobe RGB
now you can see that these two files are
现在您可以看到这两个文件是
both raw and they differ incredibly
两者都是原始的 而且差异大得令人难以置信
let's take these files into dark table
让我们把这些文件拿到暗桌上去
and let's start digging first thing
让我们开始挖掘第一件事
you'll notice that these two files still
你会注意到这两个文件仍然
look incredibly different everywhere in
在中国各地看起来都非常不同
dark table and that is because dark
黑暗的桌子 那是因为黑暗
table uses the embedded previews that
表使用嵌入的预览
are embedded in the camera native raw
被嵌入到摄像机原生RAW中
file
文件
why because it's faster
为什么？因为它更快
let's keep it that way okay let's load
让我们保持这种状态 好的 让我们装载
up the two photos into darkroom
把两张照片放进暗室
what I will do first is I will get rid
我要做的第一件事就是摆脱
of as many modules as possible these
在尽可能多的模块中
modules help us get from data to an
模块帮助我们将数据转换为
image but we want to be as close to the
图像 但我们希望尽可能接近
data part as possible some modules are
数据部分可能有些模块是
mandatory so we won't be able to disable
强制 因此我们将无法禁用
them we will be looking at nonsense for
我们将为他们寻找无稽之谈
a bit but bear with me let's take a
有点 但请原谅我 让我们拿一个
snapshot
快照
and let's move to the other photo
让我们转到另一张照片
disable all the modules once
禁用所有模块一次
you can see where this is going
你可以看到这是怎么回事
I can enable the snapshot and we can do
我可以启用快照 我们可以
a one-to-one comparison
一对一的比较
besides the moving curtain
除了移动的窗帘
these two photos are identical
这两张照片一模一样
even zoom in
甚至放大
on the colorful part
关于多姿多彩的部分
take another snapshot and compare it to
拍摄另一张快照并将其与
the other one
另一个人
see no difference
看不出有什么区别
even enable the white balance modules
甚至启用白平衡模块
and make sure they are set to d65
并确保将它们设置为D65
still the same
还是老样子
we can also enable the color calibration
我们还可以启用颜色校准
module
模块
just make sure the values are identical
只需确保值相同即可
four six three seven
四六三七
that's daylight
那是白昼
and that's how you arrive at an
这就是你如何达到一个
identical result
相同的结果
and there it is
它就在那里
we have two identical photos that were
我们有两张一模一样的照片
captured with completely different
以完全不同的方式捕获
settings
设置
and they're both look exactly the same
而且它们看起来都一模一样
just a reminder all these settings will
提醒一下 所有这些设置都将
affect your videos and JPEG files and
影响您的视频和JPEG文件 并
you have to absolutely nail them in
你必须绝对地把它们钉牢
order to preserve as much information as
为了保存尽可能多的信息
possible
可能的
for raw capturing instead of a
用于原始捕获 而不是
conclusion I'll give you a
结论我会给你一个
recommendation
推荐信
adjust these settings to your own taste
根据您的喜好调整这些设置
to get previews that closely match your
要获得与您的预览非常匹配的预览
raw developing Style
原始发展风格
if you like contrast give it a boost if
如果你喜欢对比度 给它一个提振 如果
you like the saturated colors increase
你喜欢的饱和色增加了
the saturation most importantly feel
最重要的是感受到饱和
free to keep the white balance on your
自由保持白平衡在您的
camera to Auto unless you're one of
相机设置为自动 除非您是
those people who carry a gray card in
那些拿着灰卡的人
their wallets
他们的钱包